这是普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意：回答听力部分时，
请先。
先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
听力试音时间。
I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to find out a bit
more. Yes, certainly.
Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different countries.
It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kinds of events do you Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events,
and we also have language evenings.
Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试。
日，正式开始。
请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面。
五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中，选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每段。
看对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间
来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有。
五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容：
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案
标在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，
所以你选择
项，并将其标在。试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Lucy, would you like to have lunch with me tomorrow?
Oh, I'd really love to, but I have an appointment with my dentist at 11.30.
Thanks for inviting me.
Peter, how is the weather now?
Is it still raining?
No, but there's still lots of clouds.
The weatherman said the sun wouldn't come out until next week.
I'm sorry I was late for class today, Dr.
Simpson. Well, I'll let it go this time.
But you saw it disturbed the rest of the class.
Yes, I realized that.
I won't let it happen again.
Hi, Mike. Listen, I'm coming back this afternoon, and I'll take a bus from the
railway station. So you don't need to come and pick me up.
Okay, take care, and see you soon.
Jenny, there's an opening for an assistant manager in our company.
You should give it a try.
Thank you, George, but I've decided to travel a before finding another job.
第一节到此结束。
第二节。
听下面五段对话或独白，
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，
从题中所给的
B, Listen Answer By the way, do you know what time it is?
三个选项中，选出最佳选项。
并标在试卷的相应位置。
听每段对话或独白前，
你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出。
出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白，读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答
第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
Well, it's a quarter to two.
Oh, I've got to go.
See Linda in the library?
No. Actually, I'm going to meet with Professor Smith at ten past two.
You may continue our project discussion with Michael.
All right. By the way, do know what time it is?
Well, it's a quarter to two.
Oh, I've got to go.
See Linda in the library?
No. Actually, I'm going to meet with Professor Smith at ten past two.
You may continue our project discussion with Michael.
All right. Answer questions.
听下面一段对话，回答
第八至第十三个小题。
现在你。
有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题
Harry, guess what?
I've just received an email from Pamela.
She and Peter are coming down to see us this weekend.
Oh, that's good news.
We haven't seen them for ages.
Yeah. The last time we met them was at our wedding three years ago.
Did Pamela mention how long they'll stay?
About one week.
Great. I can't wait to show them around our new house.
Me too. We haven't had any guests since we moved in here.
If the weather is fine, we can have a barbecue in the garden.
That's idea. I'll go to market tomorrow to buy all the things we'll need.
Harry, guess what?
I've just received an email from Pamela.
She and Peter are coming down to see us this weekend.
Oh, that's good news.
We haven't seen them for ages.
Yeah. The last time we met them was at our wedding three years ago.
Did Pamela mention how long they'll stay?
About one week.
Great. I can't wait to show them around our new house.
Me too. We haven't had any guests since we moved in here.
If the weather is fine, we can have a barbecue in the garden.
Good idea. I'll go to the market tomorrow to buy all the things we'll need.
听下面一段对话。
回答第十一至第十三三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Hello, everyone. Welcome to our program.
Today, we are fortunate to have a special guest with us.
Some of you may have heard of him before.
He's an artist.
His works have received many prizes and have been shown in over 100 exhibitions
across the country.
Los Angeles, New York, Philadelphia, to name just a few.
His name is Chris Cuxy.
So Chris, tell us a bit about yourself.
Well, I was born in Springfield, Missouri, and grew up in Kansas.
I didn't come from a family with wealth or position, but I did manage to get a
master's degree in fine arts.
When did you first start to art, and what was the turning point in your life that
made you an artist?
I always liked drawing as early as I could remember.
So right from then, I knew what I was going to be, an artist.
What is it that always inspires you to create?
is the biggest inspiration.
I'm always inspired by things of beauty and harmony.
Hello, everyone. Welcome to our program.
Today, we are fortunate to have a special guest with us.
Some of you may have heard of him before.
He's an artist.
His works have received many prizes and have been shown in over 100 exhibitions
across the country.
Los Angeles, New York, Philadelphia, to name just a few.
His name is Chris Cuxy.
So Chris, tell us a bit about yourself.
Well, I was born in Springfield, Missouri, and grew up in Kansas.
I didn't come from a family with wealth or position, but I did manage to get a
master's degree in fine arts.
When did you first start to art, and what was the turning point in your life that
made you an artist?
I always liked drawing as early as I could remember.
So right from then, I knew what I was going to be, an artist.
What is it that always inspires you to create?
Nature is the biggest inspiration.
I'm always inspired by things of beauty and harmony.
听下面一段对话，回答
第十四至第十七四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这。
四个小题。
Thank you. You must be pretty excited about your trip to Europe, Dorothy.
When are you leaving?
In just two weeks, and I am excited.
I've been looking forward to this training program for a long time, but there are
still a few things I need to do before I go.
Like what? Like renewing my passport and figuring out what to do with my apartment
while I'm gone.
You are not going to give it up, are you?
No way. I'll never find another apartment like it around here.
But I don't like the idea of paying three months for an empty apartment either, so
I'm looking for someone to take it while I'm away.
Um, let me think.
Oh, I know just a person.
An old colleague of mine, Jim Thomas.
He is coming here to do some research this summer from June to August.
Well, that's exactly when I'll be away.
Tell you what, I'll be calling Jim late this week anyway, so I'll mention it to him.
Well, thanks, Bill.
You must be pretty excited about your trip to Europe, Dorothy.
When are you leaving?
In just two weeks, and I am excited.
I've been looking forward to this training program for a long time, but there are
still a few things I need to do before I go.
Like what? Like renewing my passport and figuring out what to do with my apartment
while I'm gone.
You are not going to give it up, are you?
I'll never find another apartment like it around here.
But I don't like the idea of paying three months for an empty apartment either, so
I'm looking for someone to take it while I'm away.
Um, let me think.
Oh, I know just a person.
An old colleague of mine, Jim Thomas.
He is coming here to do some research this summer from June to August.
Well, that's exactly when I'll be away.
Tell you what, I'll be calling Jim late this week anyway, so I'll mention it to him.
Well, thanks, Bill.
听下面一段独白，回答。
第十八至第二十三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
I hope I've given you a clear idea of the schedule for your London weekend.
And before I finish, let me just give you some advice which should make your stay
more enjoyable. Firstly, please do remember to put on some comfortable shoes.
London is a big place and whatever you do, you'll find yourself doing quite a lot of
walking, so comfortable shoes are really necessary.
And secondly, let me ask you to please look after your money.
Keep it safe at all times, and then you will not have any unpleasant accident which
could ruin your whole weekend.
You'll find a copy of your weekend schedule in your room.
Take a look at it and make sure you're clear about everything.
Well, that's all from me for now.
Go and leave your luggage in your rooms.
I'll be seeing you here again in 15 minutes.
Goodbye for now.
I hope I've given you a clear idea of the schedule for your London weekend.
And before I finish, let me just give you some advice which should make your stay
more enjoyable. please do remember to put on some comfortable shoes.
London is a big place and whatever you do, you'll find yourself doing quite a lot of
walking, so comfortable shoes are really necessary.
And secondly, let me ask you to please look after your money.
Keep it safe at all times, and then you will not have any unpleasant accident which
could ruin your whole weekend.
You'll find a copy of your weekend schedule in your room.
Take a look at it and make sure you're clear about everything.
Well, that's all from me for now.
Go and leave your luggage in your rooms.
I'll be seeing you here again in 15 minutes.
Goodbye for now.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有。
有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. you.
听力部分到此结束。